(忆往昔)
克劳力在哪
Where is Crowley?
我不知道
I don't know!
我哥哥在哪
Where's my brother?!
小卡  我可能有发现
Cass, I think I might've found something.
实际上  你该担心自己的健康了
Actually, you need to be worrying about yourself.
我没事
I'm fine.
你要死了
You're dying.
你需要更多能量
You need more grace.
-梅塔特隆呢  -还在监狱里
- And Metatron? - Still in jail.
你是个好士兵  汉娜
You're a good soldier, Hannah...
你哥哥生龙活虎呢
Your brother is very much alive,
多亏了血印
courtesy of the mark.
血印需要血祭
The mark needs to be sated.
否则我就会变成恶魔
Otherwise, I turn into a demon.
你不能接受的是  他是我的死党
You can't stand that he's my best friend.
我们一起创建完美的地狱
Together, we create the perfect hell.
我会找到你
I am going to find you.
我会救回我哥哥
I am going to save my brother.
需要帮忙吗
Need some help?
是我的话  就不那么做  他是个禽兽
I wouldn't do that. He's a monster.
他死了吗
Is he dead?
只要你去我指定的地方
As long as you show up where I tell you to show up,
你弟弟就不会有事
your brother will be just fine.
我都叫他放我走了
I told him to let me go.
所以他现在陷入的麻烦  就只是他的问题
So whatever jam he's in now, that is his problem.
(2003年6月21日)
不  不要
No, please! Please!
别啊
Please don't!
爸爸
Dad?
Dad.
爸爸
Dad?!
Daddy.
就是那晚  迪恩·温彻斯特杀了我爸爸
And that was the night that Dean Winchester murdered my father.
所以
And that's...
所以他必须死
That's why he's gonna die.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我不需要你的同情  萨姆
I'm not looking for your sympathy, Sammy.
我要的是你哥哥
I'm looking for your brother.
告诉我迪恩在哪
So, why don't you tell me where Dean-o is,
我就放你走
and then I'll let you go.
那是不可能的
That's not gonna happen.
是嘛
Really?
你知道你哥哥告诉我  我完全可以
Now, you know your brother gave me the, uh, green light
一枪崩了你吧
to put one between your eyes, right?
迪恩
Dean...
迪恩现在不是他自己
Dean isn't Dean right now.
我不知道你是谁
Now, look, I don't know who you are...
我叫科尔
Name's Cole.
听着  萨姆
Listen, Sam...
每天晚上
Every night...
自从我13岁起
since I was 13 years old...
每天晚上  我闭上眼睛
Every night, I close my eyes...
我看到的都是你哥哥
...and all I can see is your brother...
那一地的血
And all that blood...
和我爸爸
And my daddy.
好了
Now...
我知道迪恩是你的亲人
I know Dean's family and all,
但他放弃了你
but he gave you up.
你完全没理由保护他了  完全没有
And you have no reason to protect him... none.
所以帮帮我吧
So help me.
求你了
Please.
你爸爸的事  我很遗憾
Look, I'm sorry about your dad.
不管是怎么回事
Whatever happened...
迪恩肯定自有原因
Dean had a reason.
我不知道要怎么跟你说
I don't know how to tell you this.
这世界上是有怪物的
There are monsters out there.
你以为我不知道吗
You don't think I know that?
我两次派驻伊拉克
I did two tours in Iraq.
特种部队  去过达尔富尔
Special ops, Darfur...
刚果
The Congo.
我见过人肉炸弹和童兵
I've seen suicide bombers and child soldiers
年纪小的话都说不好
so hopped up on speed that they could barely talk!
却会开机关枪
Oh, but they could sure as hell shoot an A.K.
我不是指那种怪物
Not that kind of monster.
别跟我说什么怪物
Don't tell me about monsters!
我见过不少了
'cause I've met my share.
我是指吸血鬼
I mean vampires!
明白了吗  狼人
All right? Werewolves.
真正的怪物
Monster monsters.
去看我的包
Look in the bag.
去啊
Go on.
看看  就在里面
Take a look. It's right there.
看来疯子也需要喝水
I guess even psychos need to hydrate.
那是圣水
It's holy water.
老天爷啊
Holy cow.
我不是疯子
Look, I'm not a psycho.
我也没撒谎
And I'm not lying.
撒谎的疯子也会这么说
Well, you see, that's exactly what a psycho liar would say,
所以
so...
看出我为什么为难了吧
See my dilemma?
我猜
I guess...
我们只能
we are just gonna have to do this
用另一种办法了
the other way.
[邪恶力量 第10季第2集]
(北达科他州  喧鸻镇)
只能看不能碰
No touching,
这是规矩
house rules.
你确定
You sure about that?
来啊  把钱捡起来
Go ahead, pick it up.
再见吧您啊
And we're done.
曲子还没完呢  亲爱的
Song's not over, sweetheart.
你该走了  混蛋
Time to go, jerkwad.
迪恩在哪  萨姆
Where's Dean, Sam?
他在哪
Where is he?
去死吧你
Shove it up your ass.
好吧
Okay. Okay.
好啊
Okay, okay.
看来该更进一步了
I guess it's time to crank up the volume, then.
就这里
Right there.
你真走运
Ain't you lucky, boy?
亲爱的
Hey, darling.
没事  我挺好
No, I'm good.
一切都很好  没事的
No, everything's fine. Everything's just fine.
嗯  让他接吧
Go ahead. Put him on.
小家伙  干什么呢
Big guy. How you doing?
不不  爸爸现在很忙
Now, no, no. Listen, daddy's really busy right now, okay?
我爱你
I love you.
好了  我得挂了  待会儿打给你
All right, I got to go, okay? I'm gonna have to call you back.
闪开  老头子
Move, grandpa.
这些臭小子啊
Kids. Am I right?
我那个年代  可是尊老爱幼的
In my day, we respected our elders.
不过嘛  那时候30岁以上的就是老人家了
Of course, back then, anyone over 30 was ancient.
如今40岁的人还跟妈妈一起住
Now 40-year-olds are still living with mommy,
在约会网站上撒谎  给食物拍照
lying on OkCupid, and taking pictures of their food.
你想怎么样  克劳力
What do you want, Crowley?
跟你聊聊
A chat.
我们得谈谈你的脾气问题
We need to talk about your... anger-management issues.
来
Here.
我来吧
Let me.
谢谢
Thank you.
汉娜  你不用...
Hannah, you don't have to...
你可以走的
You... you can go.
你不欠我什么
You don't owe me anything.
我知道
I know.
但我想留下
But I want to stay...
帮你
and help.
这样不对吗
Is that wrong?
不
No.
这只是很有人性
It's just...very human.
这是在夸你
It's a compliment.
萨姆
Sam.
你得去北达科他州  比乌拉  马上
You need to get to Beulah, North Dakota... now.
-是吗  -是的  克劳力和迪恩刚经过那里
- I do? - Yes. Crowley and Dean were there.
我们得追上去
We got to pick up their trail.
好  很好
Good. Great.
这个...不是很好
Yeah, um...not so much.
小卡
Cass...
迪恩是恶魔
Dean's a demon.
Dean's a demon?
怎么会
How?
大概是因为那个血印吧
The mark... I-I guess it...
肯定毁了他  我也说不好
It just messed him up. I don't know.
这么说可太轻了
That is a vast understatement.
嗯  小卡  听我说
Right. Now, Cass, listen.
我知道你现在状况不太好
I know you're not feeling so hot,
但这算是需要全员出动的情况
but this is kind of an "all hands on deck" situation here, so...
那  我们在那边见了
So... I'll meet you there.
嗯
Yeah.
你真要这么做吗
Are you sure about this?
如果你不想去
If you wanted to stay behind...
不是的  我只是
I didn't. I just...
卡西迪奥
Castiel...
我觉得温家兄弟把你带坏了
I think the Winchesters are a bad influence on you.
萨姆和迪恩虽然有些小毛病
Sam and Dean may be a bit rough around the edges,
但他们是我认识的最好的人了
but they're the best men I've ever known.
而且他们是我的朋友
And they're my friends.
我永远看不腻
I never get tired of looking at them.
那些繁星
All those stars.
两杯酒
Two shots here.
给他来点高档货  插个精致的小伞什么的
He'll have something fancy, with your tiniest umbrella.
那个
So...
你感觉如何
How you been feeling?
焦躁
On edge?
压抑
Pent-up?
欲求不满
Unfulfilled?
你活像伟哥广告
You sound like a viagra commercial.
知道吗
You know that, right?
这不是关于...小丁丁的
This isn't about... little Dean.
是关于血印  它改变了你
It's about the mark. It changed you.
我发现了
I've noticed.
我知道你想继续狂欢
And I know that you want to keep the party going.
继续享乐
You want to have fun, fun, fun
直到爸爸把黑眼去掉
till daddy takes the black eyes away.
但是
The fact is...
你现在需要杀人
You need to kill now.
不是想要  或者决定
Not want to, not choose to...
是必须
Need to.
给
There you go.
谢谢
Danke.
承认吧  亲爱的
Face it, darling.
你是瘾君子  而死亡就是你的瘾
You're an addict. Death is your drug.
你余生都要沉迷于此了
And you're gonna spend the rest of your life chasing that dragon.
那又如何
So?
所以  我要帮你
So...I'm here to facilitate.
你要我替你杀人
You want me to kill for you.
我要你替我们杀人
I want you to kill for us.
听着
Look...
你最终总会爆发的
You're going to snap eventually.
愤怒  嗜血  会在你体内渐渐积蓄
The anger, the bloodlust is gonna build up in you
直到你再也无法忍受
until you can't take it anymore,
到那时...
and then...
所以问题来了
So, the question is,
你是要杀无辜平民
do you want to spike a civilian
还是活该受死的人呢
or someone who has it coming?
比如呢
Like who?
比如
Like...
明蒂·莫里斯
Mindy Morris.
慈爱的母亲
Caring mother...
钟情的妻子
loving wife...
也是出轨的婊子
...cheating trollop.
被她丈夫莱斯特撞破奸情之后
After her husband, Lester, discovered Mindy's liaison amoureuse,
两人爆发了激烈的争吵
heated words were exchanged.
最终  明蒂决定离婚
In the end, Mindy wanted a divorce...
并要求分得一半家产
and 50% of everything.
但莱斯特
But Lester...
莱斯特宁可放弃灵魂
Lester would rather give up his soul
也不愿拱手让出家产
than half his junk.
我们就生活在一个很物质的世界里
We live in a very materialistic world.
明蒂横竖都是死
Mindy's gonna die one way or the other.
何不借这个机会  满足一下兽欲
Why not take the job... feed the beast?
好吧
Fine.
就这一次
One-time deal.
还有点别的事
Oh, there's something else that I...
我得跟你说说
need to share with you.
我得进镇去买新轮胎
I'm gonna have to run in to town for a new set of tires.
得要一阵
Could take a while.
你们想先进去看看电视什么的
You want to head inside and watch tv or something,
请随意
you're more than welcome.
冰箱里有些剩的三豆沙拉
Oh, and there's leftover three-bean surprise in the fridge,
-饿了就吃吧  -你可真好
- if you're hungry. - You're very kind.
以前杀过人  所以要行善嘛
Makes up for me being an ax murderer and all.
抱歉  开玩笑的
Uh, sorry. Kidding.
懂了
Ah, I see.
非常感谢
Thank you for everything.
豆子的部分明白了  但是...
I understand the three beans, but...
惊喜在哪啊
what's the surprise?
莱斯特吗
Let me guess... Lester?
我...你是谁
I...who are you?
你以为呢
Who do you think?
你在这儿干什么呢
What the hell are you doing here, man?
我的联络人
Well, my contact...
他说你要办事了
Yeah, he, uh... he told me that, uh, this was happening,
我想亲自过来  确保任务完成好了
so I just wanted to come down and make sure it gets done right.
因为你是这方面的专家  是吗
Ah. 'cause you're the expert, huh?
听好了  这是杀人基本规则
Listen... and this is murder 101...
如果你雇凶杀妻
when you hire someone to kill your wife,
杀手去行凶的时候绝对不要靠近案发现场
you don't want to be around when the hit goes down.
这叫不在场证明
It's called an alibi.
我知道那是什么意思
Yeah, I know what an alibi is.
我有看《小律师大作为》
I watch "Franklin & Bash""
太好了
Super.
听我说  你为这破事出卖了灵魂...
Listen, you sold your soul for this crap, so...
不是破事
It's not crap.
这是我的人生
It's my life.
却被她毁了
And she flushed it down the toilet.
莱斯特
Les...
我要跟你说些话  你得听好了
I'm gonna say something to you. I need you to really listen to me.
你就是个废物
You're a loser.
你老婆  她在北达科他州算8分了
Your lady in there... she's a North Dakota 8.
你也就4.5分吧
You're a 4 1/2, max.
我真不怪她会出轨
Now, I don't blame her for stepping out...
尤其是如果她发现是你先出轨了
Especially if she found you were messing around first.
不  我没有...
No. Oh, no. I-I wasn't...uh...
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
你就是有那种变态的
Well, you just got that, uh, pervy,
"为了能上秘书我什么都肯做"的表情
"I'd do anything to nail my secretary" look.
不不  男人这么做不是一码事
Oh. No. T-that... it's different when guys do it.
是吗
Really?
是啊  这是科学
Yeah. It's called "science""
男人天生不适合一夫一妻制
Men aren't built for monogamy...
因为进化的缘故
Because of evolution.
我们天生就是要...
We're... we're... we're programmed, you know,
散播种子的
to... to spread our seed.
听着  你个大废物
Like I said... loser, with a capital "L,"
你就是个烂人
rhymes with "You suck."
你还是恶魔呢
Yeah, well, you're a punk-ass demon!
你现在要为我工作
And you work for me now.
进去给我完成任务  你个怪物
So get in there and do your job, you freak!
那你呢  你要偷看吗
And what are you gonna do? You gonna watch, huh?
你是想这么做吗  莱斯特  看着我杀人
Is that what you like to do, Lester? Watch?
看好了
Well, watch this.
就是他
Hmm. That's the guy.
我报了警  但警察赶来前他就跑了
I called 911, but he was gone before they showed up.
那个混蛋也打了你吗
That dude get to you, too?
不是的  这是打猎时意外受的伤
Oh, uh, no. This is, uh, just a...hunting accident.
-我去  -是啊  能帮个忙吗
- Damn. - Yeah. Would you do me a favor?
如果你再见到他  能打给我吗
If you do see him again, will you give me a call?
(莱米·凯尔米斯特)
-嗯  没问题  -谢了
- Yeah. You bet. - Thanks.
你好
Hello.
你做好梦了吗
Did you have a good dream?
那个
Well...
我不做梦的
I, uh... I don't really dream.
为什么  有次我梦到我的鼻涕是火箭
Why? One time, I dreamed that my snot was a rocket,
而且它还发射到了空中  把星星打下来
and it shot into space and knocked down the stars
给更多火箭腾地方
to make room for more rockets!
听上去是很特别的鼻涕啊
That sounds like some very special snot.
好了  你们可以上路了
All right, you're good to go.
非常感谢
We appreciate that.
你男人不错啊
Great guy you have there.
我们不是...
We're not...
那种关系
That.
那可惜了
Too bad.
最终
At the end of the day,
我们只得战略性地调整期望值
we have to strategically calibrate expectations.
通过做这64个小改变
And so, by making these 64 small changes...
我相信  我们可以将恶魔转化率提高0.03%
...I believe we can increase our demon-conversion rate by 0.03%.
长官
Uh, sir?
-长官  -杀了我得了
- Sir? - Kill me.
是萨姆·温彻斯特  长官
Uh... it's Sam Winchester, sir.
他就在附近了
He's close.
迪恩
Dean!
怎么样
How did it go?
挺好的
Fine. Fine.
他死了  你说得对  我感觉棒极了
He's dead, and you're right... I-I feel amazing.
他
"He"?
莱斯特
Uh, Lester.
客户  你杀了客户
The client? You killed the client?
有什么关系  他就一混蛋  现在他是死混蛋了
Does it matter? He was a douche. Now he's a dead douche.
当然有关系了
Of course it matters!
交易是杀掉妻子换灵魂
The deal was one dead wife for one soul.
妻子没死  我得不到他的灵魂  自己算啊
The wife's not dead, I don't get the soul. It's math.
这不就是了
Well...there you go.
别背对我
Hey! Don't turn your back on me!
有什么好笑的吗
Is something funny?
没有  长官
No, sir.
很好
Good.
你这是干什么
What do you think you're doing?
我想干什么干什么
Oh, whatever I want.
是吗  我觉得你根本不知道自己想要什么
Really? Because I think you don't know what you want.
说说看  迪恩  你算什么  恶魔吗
Tell me, Dean... what are you? A demon?
如果是  那莱斯特的妻子怎么还活着
If so, why isn't Lester's wife dead?
你是不忍心吗
Did you feel sorry for her?
那或许你是人类
So maybe you're human.
只是你有双漂亮的黑眼睛
Except you have those pretty black peepers
而且你在跟我合作
and you're working alongside me.
所以你能不能帮大家个忙
Why don't you do us all a great big favor
选一边吧
and pick a bloody side?!
否则呢
Or what?
来啊
Go ahead.
出招啊
Make a move.
看看会是什么结果
See how it ends.
我不是你的死党  也不会听你指挥
I ain't your friggin' bestie, and I ain't taking orders from you.
我想杀人了  会打给你
When I need to kill, I'll call.
在此之前  别来烦我
Until then, stay out of my way.
好吧  结束了
Fine. It's over.
没办法
What can I say?
狂野的男人  只能玩玩
Crazy ones... well, they're good for a fling,
不能维持下去
but they're not relationship material.
你说完了吗
Are you done?
我们结束了
We're done.
告诉你  迪恩
You know what, Dean?
错不在我  在你
It's not me. It's you.
还是我来开车吧
Maybe I should drive?
好吧
All right.
这样也好
Good idea.
你好啊  小鹿
Hello, bullwinkle.
想我了吗
You miss me?
-想死了  -你是来找迪恩的
- So much. - You're here for Dean.
我正要把他给你
I'm here to give him to you.
-什么  -那小混蛋坏我生意
- What? - The little prat's bad for business.
他...不受控制  一定是因为血印
He's...uncontrollable. Must be the mark.
总之  迪恩又成了你的问题了  永远都是了
Anyway, Dean's your problem now... again, forever.
那他在哪
Then where is he?
首先  要谈一下我的中介费
First, there's the small matter of my finder's fee.
汉娜
Hannah?!
她走了  卡西迪奥
She's gone, Castiel.
她搭直达电梯上楼了
She took the express elevator upstairs.
去天堂了  为什么
To heaven? Why?
你好啊  美女
Hello, beautiful.
-梅塔特隆  -我就知道你会回来
- Metatron. - I knew you'd come back.
我们之间炽热的火花  我感觉到了
That white-hot spark between us... I felt it.
我是为卡西迪奥而来
I'm here about Castiel.
你施咒关闭天堂大门之后
After you cast the spell to close the gates of heaven,
他的能量还有剩吗
was there any of his grace left?
如果有呢
And if there was?
那我要拿到
Then I want it.
这个嘛
Well...
人人都有所求
Everybody wants something.
问题是  你愿付出代价吗
Question is, are you willing to pay for it?
你愿意
Are you willing to...
比如...放我出去吗
I don't know... let me out?
拜托  别那么惊讶的样子
Oh, come on. Don't look so shocked.
你肯定知道我会要求什么
You knew what I'd ask for.
如果你不是做好这个准备了  也不会来
And you wouldn't have come here if you weren't willing to pony up.
那我也很不好受
It doesn't make it any easier.
好吧
Fair enough.
那么
So...
我再给你点好处吧
Let me sweeten the pot.
我有了充足的时间
I have had time to...
思考
think.
我决定  不管地球了
And I've decided... screw earth.
你给我开锁  我就给你卡西迪奥的能量
You pop that lock, I'll give you Castiel's grace
然后我会去别的星球
and then scamper off to another planet...
甚至是别的星系
Another galaxy, even...
你再也不会看到我了
And you will never see me again.
作为交换
And in return...
你可以帮小卡满血复原
You get Cass back at full power...
强大  当权
Large and in charge.
这才是你真正想要的  对吗
And that's what you really want, isn't it?
有个大老板告诉你该怎么做
Somebody big and strong telling you what to do.
可怜的小汉娜
Poor little Hannah.
你如此迫切地希望受人统治
You're so desperate to be dominated.
说话小心点
Watch your mouth.
就像我说的  炽热的火花
Like I said -- white-hot spark.
那我们达成协议了吗
So, do we have a deal?
没有
No.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
她在干什么你清楚得很  混蛋迪奥
You know perfectly well what she's doing, Ass-tiel.
我必须得这么做  你快死了
I had to. You are dying.
她说得没错  你的确快死了
She's right. You totally are.
你闭嘴
You shut up!
他说你的能量还在
He said your grace -- it's still out there.
他在说谎  他是个骗子
He's lying. He is a liar.
言语也伤人啊
Hey, words hurt!
听我说  汉娜  你不会想这么做的
Listen to me, Hannah. You don't want this.
我见识过...
I have seen what --
我在绝望之下做出的交易
I've made deals born of desperation,
无一不以血泪告终
and they always end in blood and tears --
毫无例外
always.
难道我就应该让你...
So I'm supposed to let you...
是的  这是我的人生  也是我的选择
Yes. It's my life, and it's my choice.
而我不想要这个
And I don't want this.
我...
I...
你说的没错
You're right.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你错了
You're wrong.
不是指你说我撒谎的部分
Not about the lying part.
我的确是个说谎高手
I am a terrific liar.
但是你的能量确实还剩一些
But there is some of your mojo left.
不多...
Not a lot...
但也够用了
but enough.
你只要付出一点点代价  就能拿回去...
And it can be yours for the low, low price of --
你自己留着吧
Keep it.
你说真的吗
Seriously?
我已经接受自己的命运了
I've made peace with my fate.
现在谁在撒谎了
Who's the liar now?
想到你被锁在这儿  永世不见天日
I enjoy thinking about you locked up in here,
我就很开心
rotting until the end of time.
这是...让我高兴的事
It's my...happy place.
是吗
Yeah?
不
No.
我会出去的
I'll get out.
也许得花上一世纪
It may take a century.
也许得花上千年
May take a millennium or two,
但这破地方休想永远锁着我
but this dump will not hold me forever.
等我自由了...
And when I'm free --
偷偷预告一下...
here's a little sneak preview --
人人都得死
everybody dies.
你...
You...
你话太多了
You talk too much.
你本该一有机会就杀了我  卡西迪奥
You should have killed me when you had the chance, Castiel.
你要死了
Dead man walking!
你听到我的话了
You heard me!
你要死了
Dead man walking!!
你算什么  迪恩  恶魔吗
What are you, Dean? A demon?
或许你是人类
Maybe you're a human.
选一边吧
Pick a bloody side!
萨姆
Hiya, Sam.
哈维  你去抽支烟吧
Hey, Harv, why don't you go grab a smoke?
谁让你挂彩了
Who winged you?
你真关心吗
Does it matter?
不
Not really.
我都叫你放我走了
I told you to let me go.
你知道我做不到
You know I can't do that.
对了
By the way,
你的...小伙伴克劳力
your, uh, pal Crowley...
出卖你了
Sold you out.
挺像他会做的事
Sounds like him.
迪恩  等等
Dean, hold on a second.
你不用这样的
You don't have to do this.
我们知道怎么治愈恶魔  记得吗
Look, we know how to cure demons. You remember that?
一点拉丁文  加上大量的血
Little latin, lot of blood.
我有印象
It rings a bell.
你就没想过吗  如果我想被治愈
Did you ever stop to think that if I wanted to be cured,
当初就不会跑了
I wouldn't have bailed?
是克劳力搞的鬼
That was Crowley.
还真不是
It really wasn't.
这不重要了  好吗
It doesn't matter, all right?
反正不管发生了什么
'Cause whatever went down, whatever happened,
我们都会解决的
we will fix it.
会吗
Will we?
现在我可是竭尽全力
'cause right now, I'm doing all I can
才能控制住不去用我的牙齿...
not to come over there and rip your throat out...
撕开你的喉咙
with my teeth.
我在给你机会  萨姆  你该抓住
I'm giving you a chance, Sam. You should take it.
我不要这机会
I'm gonna have to pass.
我不会跟你一起走出那扇门的
Well, I'm not walking out that door with you.
就是不会
I'm just not.
现在你打算怎样  杀了我吗
So, what are you gonna do? Are you gonna kill me?
不
No.
为什么
Why?
你可不知道我做过什么
You don't know what I've done.
没准我是罪有应得
I might have it coming.
我不在乎
Well, I don't care.
因为你是我哥哥
Because you are my brother.
我是来带你回家的
And I'm here to take you home.
"你是我哥哥  我是来带你回家的"
"You're my brother, and I'm here to take you home."
你当是生活频道的电影吗
Yeah, what is this, a lifetime movie?
还一副楚楚可怜的眼神
With your puppy-dog eyes?
谢了  萨姆  我正需要这个
Oh, thanks, Sammy. I needed that.
你真以为那玩意会管用吗
You really think those are gonna work?
只有试试才知道了
There's one way to find out.
真的是你
It's really you.
我们见过吗
We met?
电话里聊过
Talked on the phone.
想起来了
Right. Right.
你就是那个要给萨姆脑袋来一枪的人
You're the guy who's supposed to put a bullet in Sammy's brain.
射偏了吗
Did you miss?
我想到了更好的主意
Well, I had a better idea.
我琢磨如果我让他逃跑
I figure if I let your bro escape,
他就会去找你  我只需要跟着他就行了
he'd go running to you, and all I had to do was just tag along.
现在我们终于见面了
And now here we are, finally --
迪恩·温彻斯特
Dean Winchester.
这可好  狂热粉丝
Great. A groupie.
你记得我吗
You remember me?
当然  你就是那件事的那个人
Yeah, yeah. You're that guy from that thing.
纽约州奈阿克  2003年6月21日
Nyack, New York, June 21, 2003.
我应该想起什么来吗
That supposed to ring a bell?
那晚你残忍地杀害了一个人
It was the night you gutted and murdered a man
叫做爱德华·特伦顿
by the name of Edward Trenton.
他是我父亲
He was my father.
好吧
Okay.
-"好吧"  -我不是要否认
- "Okay"? - Well, hey, I'm not saying
我剁了你老爹
I didn't slice and dice your old man.
我只是说他不是第一个
I'm just saying that he wasn't the first,
也绝不会是最后一个
and he certainly wasn't the last,
我对不上号
and they all just kind of get blended up.
那晚上  你杀人后  我看到你了
I saw you... that night... after.
你放过了我  真是愚蠢  太愚蠢了
You let me live. That was dumb -- real dumb.
我花了半生  为此刻做训练
I spent half my life training for this moment.
脑海里已经预演了成百上千次与你的对决
I've played out this fight a thousand times in my mind.
我很了解你  迪恩
And I know all about you, Dean-o.
你很厉害  真的很厉害
And you're good. Oh, you're real good.
不过  我更厉害
But, you see, I'm better.
证明啊
Prove it.
开枪吧
Take a shot.
那可算不上报复
Now, that's not payback.
这才是
This is payback.
你知道吗...
You know...
我就是说说  但也许...
and I'm just spitballing here, but, uh, maybe...
你并不像你想的那么厉害
you are not as good as you think you are.
你懂功夫吗
You know kung fu?
我什么都懂
I know everything.
那就上吧
Well, come on.
你以为会发生什么
What did you think was gonna happen, huh?
你溜达到这儿
You just stroll up here
说什么"我叫伊尼戈·蒙托亚(取自1987年电影《公主新娘》)
and say "My name is Inigo Montoya.
你杀了我父亲  受死吧"
You killed my father. Prepare to die,"
我就会老实受死吗
and I'd just roll over?
真是...悲哀啊
Well, that's just -- it makes me sad.
你根本不知道自己惹上谁了  是不是
You have no idea what you walked into here, do you?
完全不知道
None.
你是什么
What are you?
我是恶魔
I'm a demon.
动手啊
Do it!
你说过如果你见到我  就会杀了我  那动手啊
You said if you saw me, you would kill me, so do it!
我改主意了
I guess I changed my mind.
别动  结束了
Stop! It's over!
结束了  迪恩
It's over, Dean.
和你做生意很愉快
A pleasure doing business.
你打算怎么处理它
What are you gonna do with it?
扔进火山  留在月球
Toss it into a volcano, leave it on the moon.
我会想出来的
I'll get creative.
相信我
Believe me,
我和你一样不想让迪恩再碰到
I don't want Dean getting his hands on the precious
这宝贝
any more than you do.
你哥哥知道我背叛了他
Your brother knows I ratted.
他会怀恨在心
He tends to hold a grudge.
我可不想被
I don't want to get...
捅了
boned.
这样我们之间也没一笔勾销
This doesn't make us square.
如果我再看到你...
If I see you again --
得了吧  萨曼莎
Oh, stop it, Samantha.
没人喜欢受人作弄
No one likes a tease.
把你所有关于恶魔的书都给我
Give me every book you have on demons.
先生
Sir.
该动身了
It's time to move on.
真是脏死了
This thing is filthy.
这只是辆车  萨姆
It's just a car, Sam.
"这只是辆车"
"It's just a...car""
你还真是变黑暗了
You really have gone dark.
你根本想不到
You have no idea.
你知道吗  迪恩
You know what, Dean?
我看到了刚刚发生的事
I saw what happened back there.
你本可以杀了那家伙  但你没有
You could have killed that guy, and you didn't.
你对他心生怜悯
You took mercy on him.
你管那叫怜悯
You call that mercy?
想想你这一生都耗费在
Imagine you spend your whole life
追捕杀死你父亲的人上
hunting down the guy that knifed your father.
等你最终找到他
When you finally find him...
他把你当狗一样打
He whips you like a dog.
你觉得那感觉如何
How do you think that feels?
那孩子余生都会想着  他有过机会
That kid's gonna spend his whole life knowing that he had his shot
但却无法打败我
and that he couldn't beat me.
那不是怜悯
That ain't mercy.
那是我能对他做的最残忍的事
That's the worst thing I could have done to him.
我对你  萨姆
And what I'm gonna do to you, Sammy...
也不会有怜悯
Well, that ain't gonna be mercy, either.